A Guide to the Papers of the Lea and Related Families (1770-1866) 1949
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Lea and Related Families (1770-1866) 1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11209
There are 66 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This material was given to the Library by Miss Mary Price Campbell of Charlottesville, Virginia, on October 18, 1995.
Scope and Content Information
There are 66 items, (1770-1866)1949, pertaining to the Lea and allied families of Delaware and Pennsylvania. The financial papers of Thomas Lea of Wilmington, Delaware contain two letters from Joseph Lea chiefly concerning the prices of flour and wheat, papers involved with the estate of Cantwell Jones of which Lea was the executor, and miscellaneous receipts. The financial papers of William Lea of Wilmington, Delaware concern matters relating to Brandywine Mills and to the estate of his father, Thomas Lea. Among the miscellaneous financial and legal papers is a Three Shillings piece, No. 27034, dated March 25, 1776. There are newspaper clippings and notes pertaining to members of the Lea family and Brandywine Village. Printed material includes: Broadside, "Special Message of His Excellency the Governor of the State of Delaware" (February 13, 1861) and Housekeepers Almanac for the Year 1863, published in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. The sketches and illustrations include a ribbon depicting the "Women's Pavilion International Exhibition 1876"; silhouettes of Edward Lea, Margaret Marshall Lea, and Thomas Lea, Jr.; and, a photograph of Brandywine Mills.
Contents List
- Architectural Drawings [of a school]: Titled "John Lea's Book June the 11th 1807 for geography..." 1807 (Box 1)
- Financial Papers of Thomas Lea 1805-1823 (Box 1)
- Financial Papers of Thomas Lea re: Cantwell Jones estate 1801-1819 (Box 1)
- Financial Papers of William Lea (1827-1857), 1880 (Box 1)
- Financial and Legal Papers, Miscellaneous 1770-1886 (Box 1)
- Papers re: the Lea and related families 1876-1949 (Box 1)
- Printed 1861, 1863 (Box 1)
- Sketches and other Illustrations 1876, n.d. (Box 1)
- Indenture between Thomas Babb and Thomas Lea for sale of Brandywine Hundred, Newcastle County, Delaware 1794 Sept 6 (Box M-22)
- Grant from the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania to Charles Biddle for "Pine Grove," Northampton County 1795 Dec 22 (Box M-22)
- Indenture between James and Agnes Caldwell and Joseph Israel for sale of land in White Clay Creek, Newcastle County, Delaware 1798 Sept 19 (Box M-22)
- Grant from the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania to William Poyntell for "Pointpass," Northampton County 1809 Dec 13 (Box M-22)
- Indenture between Joseph Mussi and Jonas Preston and Nathan Bunker for sale of land in Mount Pleasant, Wayne County, Pennsylvania 1824 April 30 (Box M-22)
- Indenture between Jonas Preston and Nathan Bunker and Jairus Lamb for sale of land in Jackson, Susquehanna County, Pennsylvania 1828 (Box M-22)
- Draft of a tract of land in Bradford County, Pennsylvania, belonging to Will[iam] Poyntell n.d. (Othertype 14)